<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
  <?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="rfc2629.xslt" ?>
  <!-- generated by https://github.com/cabo/kramdown-rfc2629 version 1.0.27 -->

<!DOCTYPE rfc SYSTEM "rfc2629.dtd" [
<!ENTITY RFC5598 SYSTEM "http://xml2rfc.tools.ietf.org/public/rfc/bibxml/reference.RFC.5598.xml">
<!ENTITY RFC2119 SYSTEM "http://xml2rfc.tools.ietf.org/public/rfc/bibxml/reference.RFC.2119.xml">
<!ENTITY RFC7489 SYSTEM "http://xml2rfc.tools.ietf.org/public/rfc/bibxml/reference.RFC.7489.xml">
<!ENTITY RFC7960 SYSTEM "http://xml2rfc.tools.ietf.org/public/rfc/bibxml/reference.RFC.7960.xml">
<!ENTITY SELF "[I-D.ARC-MULTI]">
]>

<?rfc toc="yes"?>
<?rfc sortrefs="yes"?>
<?rfc symrefs="yes"?>

<rfc ipr="trust200902" docName="draft-ietf-dmarc-arc-multi-01" category="exp">

  <front>
    <title abbrev="ARC-Multi">Using Multiple Signing Algorithms with the ARC (Authenticated Received Chain) Protocol</title>

    <author initials="K." surname="Andersen" fullname="Kurt Andersen">
      <organization>LinkedIn</organization>
      <address>
        <postal>
          <street>1000 West Maude Ave</street>
          <city>Sunnyvale</city>
          <region>California</region>
          <code>94085</code>
          <country>US</country>
        </postal>
        <email>kurta@linkedin.com</email>
      </address>
    </author>
    <author initials="S." surname="Blank" fullname="Seth Blank" role="editor">
      <organization>ValiMail</organization>
      <address>
        <postal>
          <street>Montgomery</street>
          <city>San Francisco</city>
          <region>California</region>
          <country>US</country>
        </postal>
        <email>seth@valimail.com</email>
      </address>
    </author>
    <author initials="J." surname="Levine" fullname="John Levine" role="editor">
      <organization>Taughannock Networks</organization>
      <address>
        <postal>
          <street>PO Box 727</street>
          <city>Trumansburg</city>
          <region>New York</region>
          <country>US</country>
        </postal>
        <email>standards@taugh.com</email>
      </address>
    </author>

    <date year="2018" month="March" day="19"/>

    <area>art</area>
    <workgroup>DMARC Working Group</workgroup>
    <keyword>Internet-Draft</keyword>

    <abstract>


<t>The Authenticated Received Chain (ARC) protocol creates a mechanism whereby a
series of handlers of an email message can conduct authentication of the email
message as it passes among them on the way to its destination.</t>

<t>Initial development of ARC has been done with a single allowed signing
algorithm, but parallel work in the DCRUP working group
(https://datatracker.ietf.org/wg/dcrup/about/) is expanding the supported
algorithms. This specification defines how to extend ARC for multiple signing
algorithms.</t>



    </abstract>


  </front>

  <middle>


<section anchor="intro" title="Introduction">

<t>The Authenticated Received Chain (ARC) protocol adds a traceable chain of 
signatures that cover the handling of an email message through a chain of
intermediary handlers.</t>

<t>Initial development of ARC has been done with a single allowed signing
algorithm, but parallel work in the DCRUP working group
(https://datatracker.ietf.org/wg/dcrup/about/) is expanding the supported
algorithms. This specification defines how to extend ARC for multiple signing
algorithms.</t>

</section>
<section anchor="overview" title="Overview">

<t>In order to phase in new signing algorithms, this specification identifies how
signers and validators process ARC sets found in email messages.</t>

</section>
<section anchor="definitions-and-terminology" title="Definitions and Terminology">

<t>This section defines terms used in the rest of the document.</t>

<t>The capitalized key words “MUST”, “MUST NOT”, “REQUIRED”, “SHALL”, “SHALL NOT”, “SHOULD”,
“SHOULD NOT”, “RECOMMENDED”, “MAY”, and “OPTIONAL” in this document are to be
interpreted as described in <xref target="RFC2119"/>.</t>

<t>Because many of the core concepts and definitions are found in <xref target="RFC5598"/>,
readers should to be familiar with the contents of <xref target="RFC5598"/>, and in
particular, the potential roles of intermediaries in the delivery of email and 
the problems <xref target="RFC7960"/> created by the initial DMARC <xref target="RFC7489"/> .</t>

</section>
<section anchor="alt-sign" title="Supporting Alternate Signing Algorithms">

<t>During a period where multiple algorithms are allowed, all of the statements in
the ARC spec which refer to “exactly one set of ARC headers per instance” need
to be understood as “at least one set per instance and no more than one set per
instance per algorithm”.</t>

</section>
<section anchor="general-approach" title="General Approach">

<section anchor="signers" title="Signers">

<t>There is a separate independent signing chain for each signing algorithm.
Hence, when creating an ARC signature, a signer MUST include only other
signatures that use the same algorithm as the signature being created.</t>

<t>Wnen signing a message with no previous ARC signatures, signers MUST sign using
all supported algorithms.</t>

<t>A signer MUST continue the longest ARC chain(s) in a message with all
algorithms that it supports.  That is, if at least one of the longest chains
uses an algorithm that a signer supports, the signer continues the chain(s).
If none of the longest chains in a message use an algorithm supported by a
signer, the signer MUST NOT extend any chains, even if a shorter chain does use
a supported algorithm.</t>

</section>
<section anchor="validators" title="Validators">

<t>A validator MUST use the longest ARC chain(s) on the message.
If a validator cannot interpret the signing algorithm on any of the longest chains,
validation fails, evven if a shorter chain does use a supported algorithm.</t>

<t>If there is more than one longest chain, the overall result reported can be that of of any of
the validations.  The result used when extending an ARC chain MUST be the result
from validating that chain.</t>

</section>
</section>
<section anchor="phases-of-algorithm-evolution" title="Phases of Algorithm Evolution">

<section anchor="introductory-period" title="Introductory Period">

<t>Intermediaries MUST be able to validate ARC chains built with either algorithm
but MAY create ARC sets with either (or both) algorithm.</t>

<t>The introductory period should be at least six (6) months.</t>

</section>
<section anchor="co-existence-period" title="Co-Existence Period">

<t>Intermediaries MUST be able to validate ARC chains build with either algorithm
and MUST create ARC sets with both algorithms.  Chains ending with either
algorithm may be used for the result.</t>

</section>
<section anchor="deprecation-period" title="Deprecation Period">

<t>ARC sets built with algorithms that are being deprecated MAY be considered
valid within an ARC chain, however, intermediaries MUST NOT create additional
sets with the deprecated algorithm.</t>

<t>The deprecation period should be at least two (2) years.</t>

</section>
<section anchor="obsolescence-period" title="Obsolescence Period">

<t>ARC sets built with algorithms that are obsolete MUST NOT be considered
valid within an ARC chain. Intermediaries MUST NOT create any
sets with any obsoleted algorithm.</t>

</section>
</section>
<section anchor="privacy-considerations" title="Privacy Considerations">

<t>No unique privacy considerations are introduced by this specification beyond those
of the base <xref target="ARC-DRAFT-11"/> protocol.</t>

</section>
<section anchor="iana-considerations" title="IANA Considerations">

<t>No new IANA considerations are introduced by this specification.</t>

</section>
<section anchor="sec-con" title="Security Considerations">

<t>No new security considerations are introduced by this specification beyond those
of the base <xref target="ARC-DRAFT-11"/> protocol.</t>

</section>


  </middle>

  <back>

    <references title='Normative References'>

&RFC5598;
&RFC2119;


    </references>

    <references title='Informative References'>

&RFC7489;
&RFC7960;
<reference anchor="ARC-DRAFT-11" target="https://tools.ietf.org/html/draft-ietf-dmarc-arc-protocol-11">
  <front>
    <title>Authenticated Received Chain (ARC) Protocol (I-D-11)</title>
    <author initials="K." surname="Andersen" fullname="Kurt Andersen">
      <organization></organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="B." surname="Long" fullname="Brandon Long">
      <organization></organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="S." surname="Jones" fullname="Steven Jones">
      <organization></organization>
    </author>
    <date year="n.d."/>
  </front>
</reference>


    </references>


<section anchor="acknowledgements" title="Acknowledgements">

<t>This draft is the work of DMARC Working Group.</t>

<t>Grateful appreciation is extended to the people who provided feedback through the discuss
mailing list.</t>

</section>
<section anchor="comments-and-feedback" title="Comments and Feedback">

<t>Please address all comments, discussions, and questions to <eref target="mailto:dmarc@ietf.org">dmarc@ietf.org</eref>.</t>

</section>


  </back>
</rfc>

